Has there  ever been a story  in which nature,  God, man, and animals were
so united  in sorrow, fighting, and rejoicing together?
Ramayana: The Legend of Prince Rama is a animation,
action, adventure film directed by Ram Mohan.
In Ayodhya, the royal palace of Kosala Kingdom in Ancient India, four princes
were born to three queens, each of whom grew to great stature.
Banished for 14 years due to court intrigue, Prince Rama
retreated to the forest with his beautiful wife Sita.
When Rama vanquishes the demons of the forest, he invites the
wrath of the demon king Ravana, who kidnaps Sita.
Based on the Indian epic the Ramayana.
Rama (Voice), played by Nikhil Kapoor.
Sita (Voice), played by Raell Padamsee.
Raavana (voice), played by Uday Mathan.
Lakshman (voice) (English), played by Mishal Verma.
Hanuman (Voice) (English), played by Noel Godin.
Sugreeva (voice) (English), played by Denzil Smith.
Ramayana: The Legend of Prince Rama is a 1993 anime film co-produced by
Japan and India; produced and directed by Yugo Sako.
It is based on the Indian epic Ramayana.
The film was directed by Koichi Sasaki, Ram Mohan, and Yugo
Sako with music composed by Vanraj Bhatia.
The film was first released in India at the 24th
International Film Festival of India.
It was also screened at the 1993 Vancouver International Film Festival.
Subsequently, a Hindi dubbed version was released in the late 1990s.
On Jan 24, 2025, it was re-released in theatres in 4K with old
English dub and new dubs in Hindi, Tamil and Telugu.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
mythology, hinduism, hindu mythology, anime.